SAJJAD MAZHAR

Software Developer

@ sajjadmazharjr@gmail.com

+917003853731

Howrah, West Bengal

in sajjadmazhar

SajjadMazhar

SKILLS

GitHub



CERTIFICATES/ AWARDS

Full stack development: Devsnest | •

JavaScript Algorithm and **Data Structures freecodeca:** freecodecamp.org | • Fundamentals of Quan-

tum Computing Program: LinuxWorld India | • Youth Empowerment AI

Hackathon: KPMG, enactus, Microsoft | 🏶

ABOUT ME

I am a Software Development Engineer with over 6 months of experience in full-stack development, specializing in back-end and front-end application development also worked on cloud platforms like Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, and AWS. Adept at identifying opportunities to enhance the user experience and develop new features to improve app functionality.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Engineer | Phicode Pvt. Ltd.

AUG 2022 - Present

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Worked on a Telecom Tower management application. This application allows users to feed their tower's data (e.g tower's 3D model, images, height, location, etc.) taken from a drone.
- Developed a measuring tool using three.js to measure the length and area of the towers' 3D models and integrated it into the application.
- Used Firebase client libraries to manage Firebase database and storage for 3+ Node.js and angular projects.
- Developed, tested, and deployed applications on firebase hosting.
- Operated with AWS S3. Responsible for managing and transferring data across S3 buckets of different accounts.
- Pursued Working with Docker, AWS ECR, ECS. responsible for dockerizing applications and deployment in AWS ECS.
- Participated in developing in company's product.
- Developed 4+ components with react and integrated it with backend APIs, and run the application with **Electron.js**

Student Mentor | NavGurukul

DEC 2021 - JULY 2022

Dharamshala, Himachal Pradesh

- Mentored students for around 7 months with Python, JavaScript, and Nodejs.
- Developed teaching and leading skills and also discovered new concepts.

PROJECTS

Blog App | 😱

MAY 2022

 created a blog app with material-UI design. A user can post, edit or delete a blog. All the CRUD functionality is managed by the back-end. Also, I grouped personal blogs, saved blogs, and public blogs in separate routes.

Notelt, Notes App | 😯 | 🏶





JUNE 2022

• In this notes app, I implemented authentication and authorization. Without authentication, the user will not be able to perform any CRUD operation on his notes. Each user has his own notes which will be visible to him after he signs in.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. | Shibpur Dinobundhoo Institution (College)

MAY 2017 - OCT 2020

• Howrah, West Bengal

• PERCENTAGE: 72